<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clairehh</title>
    <link>https://clairehhelms.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on clairehh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 22:03:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://clairehhelms.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01: LUNA</title>
      <link>https://clairehhelms.github.io/posts/moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 22:03:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clairehhelms.github.io/posts/moon/</guid>
      <description>THE MOON Earth&amp;rsquo;s natural satellite, humans&amp;rsquo; perpetual muse, and mythology&amp;rsquo;s anti-sun. The Moon is responsible for a natural rhythm that shapes the tides, the circalunar clocks of nature, and the consistency of seasons. On the more romantic side, the Moon is well-known for its presence in songs, poems, paintings, and other musings (not to mention the pop culture references&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Twilight).
Still, however familiar we feel with the Moon, most of us have never inspected it more closely than with the naked eye.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-moon&#34;&gt;THE MOON&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth&amp;rsquo;s natural satellite, humans&amp;rsquo; perpetual muse, and mythology&amp;rsquo;s anti-sun. The Moon is responsible for a natural rhythm that shapes the tides, the circalunar clocks of nature, and the consistency of seasons. On the more romantic side, the Moon is well-known for its presence in songs, poems, paintings, and other musings (not to mention the pop culture references&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Twilight).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, however familiar we feel with the Moon, most of us have never inspected it more closely than with the naked eye. I remember my first time viewing the Moon through a telescope and gazing in wonderment at its perfectly-defined craters lowlighted by shadows. I also realize after witnessing others&amp;rsquo; reactions this response is near-universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only natural, then, that the Moon is the first object I capture in my astrophotography class. To create my image, I used an observation made by Alex Shoaf on the PROMPT-6 optical telescope in Chile using Skynet Robotic Telescope Network&amp;rsquo;s interface. Because the field of view on PROMPT-6 is smaller than the Moon itself, we observed the Moon in a 3x3 dithering pattern, creating a grid of 9 seperate images which we stitched together using Afterglow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also took multiple exposures of each image, which we correlated to colors. For red, we took an exposure in H-alpha; for green, in OIII; and for blue, U. By layering these three colored images atop each other, a more natural color image was created!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://clairehhelms.github.io/moons_color.png&#34; alt=&#34;Red, green, and blue moons&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After stacking, I played with typical photograph attributes, like saturation, temperature, contrast, and exposure. I also rotated the image. My final image shows off the Moon&amp;rsquo;s greens, browns, yellows, blues, and greys. I tried to enhance the saturation and contrast of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s maria while keeping the bright areas of the Moon luminescent. At the end, I sent my image through a processor that sharpened it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://clairehhelms.github.io/moon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Final colored moon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caption: My first astrophotogrphy project! It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder how the Moon inspires when seen in this way. The Moon lives in more than just grayscale; shades of blue, green, brown, and more are on full display on its textured surface. Fun fact: this image is actually composed of 27 smaller images!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colors of the Moon are due to its minerology – blue tones reveal areas of mainly titanium (but also iron and oxygen); the yellow areas are composed of dark orange and yellow glassy deposits; brown areas were once seas filled with brown, iron-rich lava; and light gray/white areas encounter greater exposure to sunlight. Check out some of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s most prominent features!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://clairehhelms.github.io/moon_labeled.png&#34; alt=&#34;Moon with features labeled&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I am happy with what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from capturing the Moon, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to create more images!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
